To live would be an awfully big adventure.
Hook is a adventure, fantasy, comedy film directed by Steven Spielberg.
The boy who wasn't supposed to grow up—Peter Pan—does just that, becoming a soulless
corporate lawyer whose workaholism could cost him his wife and kids.
During his trip to see Granny Wendy in London, the vengeful Capt.
Hook kidnaps Peter's kids and forces Peter to return to Neverland.
Captain Hook, played by Dustin Hoffman.
Peter Banning / Peter Pan, played by Robin Williams.
Tinkerbell, played by Julia Roberts.
Smee, played by Bob Hoskins.
Granny Wendy, played by Maggie Smith.
Moira, played by Caroline Goodall.
Hook is a 1991 American fantasy adventure film directed by
Steven Spielberg and written by James V.
Hart and Malia Scotch Marmo.
It stars Robin Williams as Peter Banning / Peter Pan, Dustin Hoffman as
Captain Hook, Julia Roberts as Tinker Bell, Bob Hoskins as Mr.
Smee, Maggie Smith as Granny Wendy and Charlie Korsmo as Jack Banning.
It serves as a sequel in a modern day setting to J.
Barrie's 1911 novel Peter and Wendy, focusing on an adult Peter Pan who has
forgotten his childhood due to his high-powered lifestyle.
In his new life, he is known as Peter Banning, a successful but career-minded lawyer
who neglects his wife (Wendy's granddaughter) and their two children.
However, when his old archenemy, Captain Hook, kidnaps his
children, he returns to Neverland to save them.
Along the journey, he reclaims the memories of his past
and develops full emotional maturity.
Spielberg began developing Hook in the early 1980s with Walt
Disney Productions and Paramount Pictures.
It would have followed the Peter Pan storyline seen in the 1924
silent film and Disney Animation's 1953 film.
It entered pre-production in 1985, but Spielberg abandoned the project.
Hart developed the script with director Nick Castle and TriStar
Pictures before Spielberg decided to direct in 1989.
It was shot almost entirely on sound stages at Sony
Pictures Studios in Culver City, California.
Released on December 11, 1991, Hook received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances (particularly those of Williams
and Hoffman), John Williams' musical score, and the film's production values, but criticized the screenplay and tone.
The film also received five nominations at the 64th Academy Awards.
Although the film was a commercial success and became the
fourth-highest-grossing film of 1991, it failed to meet the studio's expectations.
Since its release, Hook gained a strong cult following, and it
is considered by many to be a cult classic.
The film explores themes of rescue, daughter, flying, swordplay, sword.
The tone is lighthearted.